Okay. So, um, we are going to be working
on this project. It is project time
again. This project is called dice
roller. I'm going to have you edit
script.js,
add two functions to make it all work.
Basically, what we're building is we're
building a dice roller that will allow
you to select dice to no longer roll and
to reroll the remaining dice. Um, so
this is what the user interface looks
like. When you click on these, um, if
you've written the functions correctly,
they'll be surrounded by a halo. And
when you click roll dice, they will no
longer roll. Only the ones that are
unselected will still roll. Um,
and so
the project repository, um, when you
clone it to your computer, it will look
like this. Um, in the images folder is
an image for each face of a die. And the
instructions, as you saw,
are right here in the readme file. Um,
and so good luck. If you are good from
here, good luck. If you've never forked
a repository before, then I'm going to
show you how to do that. So the way you
want to work on this is you'll click
this fork button. And then it'll ask you
to give it a name and make sure that
you're the owner. You'll give it a name.
Um,
and I'm going to leave everything and
I'm going to click copy the main branch
only and then click create fork. What
this does is it takes the repository
from Toa Teaches Tech and copies it to
the repos to the account that you're
logged in as. Um, in this case, I'm
logged in as my main account and so I
was able to copy it over.
Forking is really nice because it allows
um people to have open source software.
What it does is you can copy their code
to your account, make changes on your
account, and then push changes back to
their account. And they don't have to
give you access to the repository. they
can just review your changes and merge
them without you having direct right
access to their repository. In this
case, you're just copying the project so
you can have access to the project. Um,
so what you're going to do is you're
going to come to settings on this
repository once it's been forked or
copied and you're going to scroll all
the way down to the bottom and you're
going to click leave fork network. Um,
what it's saying is this will now become
a standalone repository basically as if
you had created it from scratch
yourself. you won't be pushing any
changes to the tool teaches tech
repository and you can say I have read
and understand these conditions. Then
it's going to ask you to confirm that
you have in fact read it. So you're
going to copy that, paste that there and
click leave fork network. Once you've
done that, this just becomes a standard
repository. So you've got access to
everything here. Any pull requests um
that you make will be made to your own
repository and not to the main
repository that you copied. All right.